Amaninder Singh

343-297-8696 | amandeolofficial@gmail.com | Ottawa, ON K1K 1X4

SKILLS

- Customer support needs assessment
- Client onboarding and retention
- Customer support excellence
- Logical and Creative thinkingTechnical Troubleshooting
- HTML, CSS, and Javascript
 - Microsoft Office and G Suite

API Integration and programming

- Product documentation
- SaaS applications

SUMMARY

Experienced customer support professional with over 7 years of experience and readiness to take on any team need or customer challenge. Calm and composed in stressful situations with successful record of reducing customer dissatisfaction through acknowledgment, decisive communication and focused solutions. Expert at finding win-win solutions.

EXPERIENCE

L2 Customer Support Specialist, Crossover, May 2018-Current

- Retained by Crossover (ESW Capital) after they acquired the Kayako Support Software
- Developed training materials, conducted webinars and authored wikis for user training and support use.
- Assessed customer bug reports and enhancement requests and prioritized development to streamline response.
- Collaborated with the knowledge team to assist client stakeholders with emergent technical issues and develop effective solutions.
- Reviewed support cases for technical and troubleshooting accuracy and identified needed improvements in processes.
- Documented repair processes and helped streamline procedures for future technical support actions.

Customer Success Advocate, Kayako, July 2015-May 2018

- Directed account management and customer training on company technical software and tools for new accounts and new users.
- Contributed to the ongoing learning and success of the team by sharing knowledge through mentorship, collaboration, and process documentation
- Escalated customer satisfaction ratings by offering valuable insights to customers' needs and expectations.
- Aided senior leadership during executive decision-making processes and generated daily reports to recommend corrective actions and improvements.
- Automated the booking process for virtual meetings with customers and helped Kayako reduce the resolution times.
- Designed and implemented 20+ integration solutions using Kayako API, Zapier, and Webhooks
- Devised and conducted continuous best practice webinar sessions with the sales team
- Led the social media support team along with the Director of Support -Sarah Chambers

Software Support Engineer, Kayako, July 2014-July 2015

- Offered direct engineering support for Kayako Software, maintaining ticket resolution rate of 100%
- Communicated directly with customers to answer questions and address issues concerning Kayako API, SDK and integrations
- Developed troubleshooting roadmaps and scenario manuals for knowledgebase and internal documentation.
- Identified, reproduced, and documented the customer issues for the engineering teams
 Analyzed data from IIRA software and used output to help product team with release
- Analyzed data from JIRA software and used output to help product team with release management
- Inspected software for compliance with defined supportability metrics, confirming presence of adequate post-sale support options.
 Undated software versions with patches and new installations to close security loops.
- Updated software versions with patches and new installations to close security loopholes and protect users.

Client Technical Support Associate, Dell, June 2013-July 2014

- Resolved Level 1 technical issues with Dell hardware, software and peripherals.
- Recorded complaints, product deficiencies, returned orders and other customer documentation in system.
- Identified system and network problems by implementing troubleshooting techniques.

Computer Lab Technician, CTIMT, July 2012-March 2013

- Supported individuals having data connectivity issues, assisting with troubleshooting steps and rebooting of hardware.
- Reviewed current hardware and software and recommended modifications to increase system speed.
- Performed daily maintenance of computer systems to keep network processes fluid.
- Configured new employee work stations, including all hardware, software and peripheral devices.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Computer Applications Punjab Technical University, India May 2015

Bachelor of Computer Applications
Guru Nanak Dev University, India September 2011

CERTIFICATIONS

- Content Marketing Certified
 LubSpot Academy
- HubSpot AcademyInbound Certified
- HubSpot Academy

REFERRENCES

- Vinay Sharma at Crossover (vinay.sharma170985@gmail.com)
- Gary McGrath at Paddle (garygbm@outlook.com)
- Tina Phillips at Paddle (tina@mypaperfamily.com)
- Sarah Chambers at Supported Content (sarah@supportedcontent.com)

WEBSITES

• amaninder.com